A haunting tale of sexuality in a country gone wrong.
The Handmaid's Tale is a drama, science fiction
film directed by Volker Schlöndorff.
In a dystopian, polluted right-wing religious tyranny, a young woman is
put in sexual slavery on account of her now rare fertility.
Kate, played by Natasha Richardson.
Serena Joy, played by Faye Dunaway.
Nick, played by Aidan Quinn.
Moira, played by Elizabeth McGovern.
Aunt Lydia, played by Victoria Tennant.
Commander, played by Robert Duvall.
The Handmaid's Tale is a 1990 dystopian film adapted from Canadian
author Margaret Atwood's 1985 novel of the same name.
Directed by Volker Schlöndorff, the film stars Natasha Richardson (Offred), Faye Dunaway (Serena
Joy), Robert Duvall (The Commander), Aidan Quinn (Nick), and Elizabeth McGovern (Moira).
The screenplay was written by playwright Harold Pinter.
The original music score was composed by Ryuichi Sakamoto.
The film was entered into the 40th Berlin International Film Festival.
It is the first filmed adaptation of the novel, succeeded by the
Hulu television series which began streaming in 2017.
The film adaptation of The Handmaid's Tale faced numerous challenges in its development, with screenwriter Harold Pinter
expressing dissatisfaction with the final product due to significant alterations from his original script.
Pinter had contributed only part of the screenplay and ultimately gave
the director and author carte blanche to make changes.
He tried to have his name removed from the credits but was unsuccessful.
The film's reception was lukewarm, with critics expressing
uncertainty about the movie's message and themes.
The film explores themes of rebellion, future,
canada, rape, based on novel or book.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.